<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on Center for Medical Genomics</title>
    <link>/event/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on Center for Medical Genomics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2025 Center for Medical Genomics</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>1) Noise Cancelling Repeat Finder 2) Sabutan</title>
      <link>/event/2018-09-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2018-09-05/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1H-NMR Metabolomics Reveals Associations With Child BMI at 2 Years</title>
      <link>/event/2020-09-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2020-09-09/</guid>
      <description>http://www.bx.psu.edu/makova_lab/project/childhood_obesity/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8th Translational Research in Mitochondria, Aging, and Disease (TRiMAD) Symposium</title>
      <link>/event/2018-09-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2018-09-21/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A population-phylogenetic approach to understanding mitochondrial heteroplasmy</title>
      <link>/event/2018-04-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2018-04-11/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Modeling Microbiome and Gene Expression Data</title>
      <link>/event/2025-03-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2025-03-19/</guid>
      <description>Abstract In microbiome and gene expression studies, sequencing depth is typically arbitrary and does not reflect the biological systems’ size (e.g., total microbial load) being studied. This problem is well known and is the impetus for using normalizations when analyzing these data. Previously, we showed that normalizations make strong, implicit, and often unreasonable biological assumptions that should be avoided. Two viable approaches remain: Scale Invariant and Scale Reliant Inference. In this talk, I will discuss recent advances in both types of modeling, introduce the core concepts behind these approaches, and introduce tools available to researchers looking to perform these analyses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ampliconic Genes on the Great Ape Y Chromosomes: Rapid Evolution of Copy Number but Conservation of Expression Levels</title>
      <link>/event/2020-02-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2020-02-26/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andrew H. Moeller, Martine Peeters, Jean-Basco Ndjango, et al. 2013. Sympatric chimpanzees and gorillas harbor convergent gut microbial communities. Genome Research Oct;23(10):1715-20</title>
      <link>/event/2014-03-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2014-03-21/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animal mitochondrial DNA as we don&#39;t know it: mt-genome organization and evolution in non-bilaterian lineages</title>
      <link>/event/2016-02-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2016-02-26/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annual Retreat</title>
      <link>/event/2016-05-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2016-05-19/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annual Retreat of the Center for Medical Genomics</title>
      <link>/event/2018-05-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2018-05-22/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the BG program: Nucleosomes positioning and RNA biology</title>
      <link>/event/2026-01-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2026-01-28/</guid>
      <description>Abstract  Nucleosomes Positioning - Existing algorithms can only predict the rotational setting of 65% of human nucleosomes. To uncover novel factors responsible for nucleosome positioning, we reconstituted H2A/H4 N-tailless nucleosomes in vitro. The H2A N-tail displayed an interaction with the AT content at SuperHelical Locations (SHL) ±4 and the H4 N-tail at SHL ±1 and SHL ±2, suggesting the importance of the tails in selecting nucleosome positions. Nucleosomes may reposition in cancer - Using high-resolution nucleosome maps in breast cancer patients, we detected 20-fold enrichment of nucleosome repositioning at CpG islands and a 5-10 bp decrease in the nucleosome repeat length (NRL), the latter being qualitatively similar to the differences between pluripotent and differentiated cells, as well as correlated with gene activity, differential DNA methylation and changes in local occupancy of linker histones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bioinformatics and Genomics Retreat</title>
      <link>/event/2013-10-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2013-10-04/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bioinformatics and Genomics Retreat</title>
      <link>/event/2014-09-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2014-09-12/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Bipolar: Convergence of Mitochondrial, Circadian, and Ion Channel Dysfunction</title>
      <link>/event/2019-10-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2019-10-09/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CMash: probabilistic analysis of metagenomic data</title>
      <link>/event/2018-02-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2018-02-14/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancer data analyses: from SNVs in targeted sequencing data to cell-type specific biomarkers</title>
      <link>/event/2021-12-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2021-12-08/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Center for Medical Genomics Retreat</title>
      <link>/event/2024-09-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2024-09-25/</guid>
      <description>  Bio </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterization of the tumor immune microenvironment in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma using high-plex spatial proteo-transcriptomics</title>
      <link>/event/2024-03-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2024-03-20/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Bio Martin Hemberg is an assistant professor in Harvard Medical School. His group carries out research in computational genomics, and their interests are in developing and applying algorithms for analyzing large high-throughput datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of animal and protozoan genomes suggests that neuronal ion channels are not so neuronal after all</title>
      <link>/event/2024-09-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2024-09-18/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Neuronal communication in animals depends on complex electrical signals shaped by large suites of functionally diverse voltage-gated ion channels. While these channels are based on molecular designs that first evolved in prokaryotes, it has long been assumed that the neuronal signaling requires functionally unique gene families that will have evolved specifically within the animal lineage. The recent explosion of sequence data from diverse eukaryotes, including most protozoan lineages, has provided the opportunity to revisit these assumptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complete genomes of a multi-generational pedigree to expand studies of genetic and epigenetic inheritance</title>
      <link>/event/2023-10-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2023-10-11/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The complete genomes provide an opportunity for a new biological discovery in repetitive parts of the genomes that were frequently missing, incomplete, or misrepresented in the past, such as centromeres. Here, we present a study aiming to release complete, T2T diploid assemblies of four individuals, representing a three-generational pedigree of African-American ancestry. To this end, we have utilized a combination of high-coverage, long-read (51x HiFi, PacBio, and 71x Nanopore Ultra-long data 100kb+, Oxford Nanopore Technologies) and short-read paired technologies for haplotype phasing (including 76x coverage Omni-C, Cantata Genomics, 39x paired read parental data for trio-based phasing, as well as Strandseq and Pore-C data).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complete sequences and evolutionary analysis of great ape sex chromosomes</title>
      <link>/event/2024-10-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2024-10-16/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Apes possess two sex chromosomes-the male-specific Y chromosome and the X chromosome, which is present in both males and females. The Y chromosome is crucial for male reproduction, with deletions being linked to infertility. The X chromosome is vital for reproduction and cognition. Variation in mating patterns and brain function among apes suggests corresponding differences in their sex chromosomes. However, owing to their repetitive nature and incomplete reference assemblies, ape sex chromosomes have been challenging to study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting the dots</title>
      <link>/event/2020-04-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2020-04-09/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conservation genomics in inbred Scandinavian wolves</title>
      <link>/event/2023-11-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2023-11-15/</guid>
      <description>Abstract With the recent and unprecedented progress in retrieving DNA sequence information from a large number of individuals of any species, conservation genetic research has entered a new phase. Specifically, it has become possible to study how genomes of endangered species respond to reductions in population size. Using genomic and bioinformatic approaches, in this thesis I investigate the contemporary Scandinavian wolf population founded 40 years ago by only three individuals, after the original population had been extirpated some decades earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contribution of Mitochondrial Genomics to the Congenital Cardiac and Palatal Phenotypic Variability in 22q11 2 Deletion Syndrome</title>
      <link>/event/2020-11-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2020-11-11/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crow genomics – populations, phenotypes and genome structure</title>
      <link>/event/2018-05-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2018-05-16/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNA barcoding for species classification: methods, algorithms, results</title>
      <link>/event/2015-10-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2015-10-15/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNA lesions - an important source of bias in ultrasensitive mutation detection</title>
      <link>/event/2016-08-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2016-08-31/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data-driven approaches to understand patterns in complex human diseases</title>
      <link>/event/2025-03-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2025-03-26/</guid>
      <description>Abstract In this talk, I will discuss some statistical and computational approaches we are using to integrate multiple layers of big data (including multi-omics, neuroimaging and electronic health records) from large-scaled biobanks to understand genetic overlaps between the brain and complex human diseases, predict risk of disease 5 to 10 years in advance as well as time-of-onset of disease, and present some interactive data visualization tools.
Bio Dr. Yogasudha (Sudha) Veturi, Ph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debmalya: Covariate Information Number for Feature Screening in Ultrahigh-Dimensional Supervised Learning; Lucilla: 16p12.1 Deletion as a Model for the Complex Genetics of Neurodevelopmental Disease</title>
      <link>/event/2018-08-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2018-08-29/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering the Sequence of Gorilla Y Chromosome and &#34;amplicomics&#34; of fertility genes</title>
      <link>/event/2015-04-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2015-04-16/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering the horizontal traffic rules of aminoglycoside resistance genes</title>
      <link>/event/2023-04-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2023-04-26/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of genetic information in pathogenic microorganisms: Implications for diagnostics and epidemiology</title>
      <link>/event/2014-10-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2014-10-09/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolutionary consequences of asexual reproduction on a wasp genome</title>
      <link>/event/2017-04-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2017-04-19/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the effects of mitonuclear DNA discordance on mtDNA gene expression</title>
      <link>/event/2021-10-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2021-10-27/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally, after 2 billion years, the mitochondrion is part of the general cellular regulation</title>
      <link>/event/2014-06-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2014-06-06/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frontiers public lecture: Predicting mutation and disease occurrence from DNA and omics data</title>
      <link>/event/2020-02-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2020-02-22/</guid>
      <description>With affordable DNA sequencing, information on mutations in an individual’s genome is readily available. Kateryna Makova will present how mutation frequency depends on gender, age, and DNA location. Statistical models explaining and predicting mutation occurrence and applications to pregnancy planning and genetic counseling will be discussed. Mutations can cause numerous human genetic diseases but are only one contributor to the probability of disease development for an individual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>G-quadruplexes mark sites of differential methylation in metabolic diseases</title>
      <link>/event/2024-05-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2024-05-08/</guid>
      <description> Abstract Bio </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GEMINI: Integrative Exploration of Genetic Variation and Genome Annotations discussion by Daniel Blankenberg using paper from Paila 2013</title>
      <link>/event/2013-10-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2013-10-18/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genomics Journal Club - RNA editing</title>
      <link>/event/2015-09-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2015-09-29/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genomics, Conservation, and Island Biogeography in the Caribbean</title>
      <link>/event/2019-08-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2019-08-30/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great ape genetic diversity and population history discussion by Arkarachai using paper from Prado-Martinez and Sudmant 2013</title>
      <link>/event/2013-09-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2013-09-20/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How sequencing technologies helped move transposable elements from trash to evolutionary players</title>
      <link>/event/2023-05-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2023-05-31/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypermutable DNA chronicles the evolution of human colon cancer (Naxerovaa 2014) PNAS</title>
      <link>/event/2014-09-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2014-09-05/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improvements in Discovery and Fine-Mapping of Obesity-Related Traits with Diverse Ancestral Samples</title>
      <link>/event/2020-10-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2020-10-14/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infant weight gain trajectories linked to oral microbiome composition</title>
      <link>/event/2017-09-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2017-09-20/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrative Modeling of Multiscale Single-Cell Spatial Epigenome</title>
      <link>/event/2023-11-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2023-11-08/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Despite significant advancements in high-throughput data acquisition in genomics and cell biology, our understanding of the diverse cell types within the human body remains limited. Particularly, the principles governing intracellular molecular spatial organization and cellular spatial organization within complex tissues are still largely unclear. A major challenge lies in developing computational methods capable of integrating heterogeneous and multiscale molecular, cellular, and tissue information. In this talk, I will discuss our recent work on creating integrative approaches for single-cell spatial epigenomics and transcriptomics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating Mito-nuclear Interactions in Admixed Human Populations</title>
      <link>/event/2018-09-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2018-09-12/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IsoCon: deciphering highly similar multigene family transcripts from Iso-Seq data</title>
      <link>/event/2018-03-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2018-03-21/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locating benzo[a]pyrene-DNA damage in the genome</title>
      <link>/event/2013-10-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2013-10-08/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making scents of metabolic disease: Tracking metabolic health through exhaled breath metabolomics</title>
      <link>/event/2021-04-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2021-04-14/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maternal Age Effect and Severe Germline Bottleneck in the Inheritance of Human Mitochondrial DNA</title>
      <link>/event/2014-12-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2014-12-11/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meiotic Crossover Interference -- Modeling, Heterogeneity and Inter-Pathway Cross-Talk</title>
      <link>/event/2014-09-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2014-09-11/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial genomics - ancient evolutionary challenges in regulating a bigenomic system</title>
      <link>/event/2023-05-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2023-05-15/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial transcriptional regulation – more complex than once thought</title>
      <link>/event/2018-01-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2018-01-12/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitonuclear linkage disequilibrium in human populations, Sloan et. al.</title>
      <link>/event/2015-11-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2015-11-30/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model-based block clustering with EM algorithm</title>
      <link>/event/2014-02-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2014-02-14/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiscale Modeling and Design of Biological Molecules</title>
      <link>/event/2018-08-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2018-08-22/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N/A</title>
      <link>/event/2014-09-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2014-09-19/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NGS for liquid biopsy – analyses of single circulating tumor cells and extracellular vesicles from blood samples of cancer patients</title>
      <link>/event/2017-01-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2017-01-18/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Techniques to Analyze the Microbiome: analyze thousands of samples, compare without a reference, and profile a community down to the strain level</title>
      <link>/event/2015-02-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2015-02-12/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New insights into the variation and evolution of human centromeres</title>
      <link>/event/2025-12-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2025-12-10/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Advances in long-read sequencing technologies and genome assembly algorithms have enabled the complete sequence assembly of centromeres in several human genomes. However, the variation in centromeres across individuals, populations, and evolutionary contexts remain largely unexplored, leaving the global landscape of centromere diversity poorly understood. Here, we sought to expand our understanding of centromere variation and evolution by generating complete sequence assemblies of thousands of human centromeres from individuals spanning 5 continental and 28 population groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-B DNA affects polymerization speed and error rate in sequencers and living cells</title>
      <link>/event/2017-10-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2017-10-11/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-canonical DNA in bird telomere-to-telomere genomes</title>
      <link>/event/2026-01-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2026-01-21/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Non-canonical (non-B) DNA motifs are genomic sequences capable of folding into three-dimensional structures distinct from the canonical right-handed helix. These structures regulate gene expression but also serve as mutation hotspots and are linked to cancer. Because non-B DNA is difficult to sequence, its annotations have been in-complete in most genome assemblies. Telomere-to-telomere (T2T) assemblies now overcome this limitation. Here, we provide a comprehensive analysis of seven types of non-B DNA motifs (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-canonical DNA in human and other ape cells with telomere-to-telomere genomes</title>
      <link>/event/2025-10-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2025-10-22/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Non-canonical DNA secondary structures (non-B DNA), such as G-quadruplexes and triplex DNA, are mutation hotspots and genome regulators contributing to disease and evolution. Yet they remain poorly characterized in vivo in completely sequenced genomes. Many non-B DNA structures induce single-stranded DNA (ssDNA) formation. Here, using Permanganate/S1 footprinting with Direct Adapter Ligation and Sequencing (PDAL-Seq) across 14 cell lines, we generated comparative ssDNA profiles for human and six non-human ape telomere-to-telomere (T2T) genomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-canonical DNA in human and other ape telomere-to-telomere genomes</title>
      <link>/event/2024-11-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2024-11-06/</guid>
      <description> Abstract Bio </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nucleosomes: regulators and protectors</title>
      <link>/event/2016-03-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2016-03-18/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nucleotide variability at its limit? Insights into the number and evolutionary dynamics of the sex-determining specificities of the honey bee Apis mellifera.</title>
      <link>/event/2014-02-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2014-02-21/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On nuisance events, junk DNA, and determining the impact of genomic pariah on human disease</title>
      <link>/event/2015-08-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2015-08-27/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paternally expressed genes predominate in the placenta (Wang 2013) PNAS</title>
      <link>/event/2014-10-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2014-10-03/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peak shape clustering: an application to GATA-1</title>
      <link>/event/2014-11-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2014-11-13/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physiology Retreat 2014</title>
      <link>/event/2014-11-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2014-11-07/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population-Scale Centromere Genomics in the Pangenome Era</title>
      <link>/event/2026-02-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2026-02-10/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The Human Pangenome Reference Consortium (HPRC) Release 2 represents a major milestone in reference genomics, comprising 470 high-quality, phased haplotypes from 232 globally diverse individuals. These telomere-to-telomere assemblies achieve unprecedented completeness in previously inaccessible regions, including centromeres, subtelomeres, and segmental duplications, providing a foundation for studying complex genomic regions that have been systematically excluded from population-scale analyses. In this talk, I will first present key improvements and data from HPRC Release 2, then focus on two complementary advances that unlock centromere biology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy preserving data sharing for genome-wide association studies</title>
      <link>/event/2013-11-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2013-11-12/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNA expression profiling of archival formalin-fixed, paraffin embedded tissues</title>
      <link>/event/2014-04-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2014-04-11/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recombination Dynamics of a Human Y-Chromosomal Palindrome: Rapid GC-Biased Gene Conversion, Multi-kilobase Conversion Tracts, and Rare Inversions. Plos Genetics</title>
      <link>/event/2014-04-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2014-04-04/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redefining Virus Evolution and Emergence Using Metatranscriptomics</title>
      <link>/event/2025-04-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2025-04-14/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Bio Professor Edward Holmes is a leading expert on the evolution and emergence of infectious diseases, focusing on how RNA viruses cross species boundaries to infect humans and animals. He is currently a Professor of Virology at the University of Sydney. Dr. Holmes has focused on the molecular genetics of viral transmission across species, including the mechanisms behind emerging viruses like SARS-CoV-2, influenza, and HIV. His research aims to uncover why certain pathogens are more likely to jump between species and spread, while using methods like metagenomics to discover new viruses and investigate disease patterns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research and Clinical Questions in Perioperative Genomics</title>
      <link>/event/2013-12-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2013-12-10/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selective propagation of functional mitochondrial DNA during oogenesis restricts the transmission of a deleterious mitochondrial variant. Nature Genetics</title>
      <link>/event/2014-04-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2014-04-18/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selfish mutations are important drivers of the paternal age effect</title>
      <link>/event/2016-10-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2016-10-24/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sex-biased evolution and disease</title>
      <link>/event/2013-09-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2013-09-10/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-cell RNA-sequencing Reveals Profibrotic Roles of Distinct Epithelial and Mesenchymal Lineages in Pulmonary Fibrosis</title>
      <link>/event/2020-02-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2020-02-12/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical analyses of expression measurements in RNA from archival formalin-fixed, paraffin embedded tissues</title>
      <link>/event/2015-11-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2015-11-05/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical and Biophysics-inspired Methods for Discovery of Gene Regulatory Mechanisms</title>
      <link>/event/2018-09-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2018-09-19/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stem Cell Models for Studying Normal and Malignant Hematopoiesis</title>
      <link>/event/2019-11-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2019-11-13/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structured Nucleic Acids Day</title>
      <link>/event/2023-04-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2023-04-18/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Studies of genome evolution in non-traditional model organisms</title>
      <link>/event/2017-11-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2017-11-08/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TBA</title>
      <link>/event/2018-11-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2018-11-07/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TBA</title>
      <link>/event/2018-11-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2018-11-14/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TBA</title>
      <link>/event/2018-11-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2018-11-21/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TBA</title>
      <link>/event/2018-11-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2018-11-28/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TBA</title>
      <link>/event/2018-12-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2018-12-05/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TBA</title>
      <link>/event/2018-12-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2018-12-12/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TBA</title>
      <link>/event/2018-12-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2018-12-19/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TBD</title>
      <link>/event/2025-02-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2025-02-19/</guid>
      <description> Abstract Bio </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telomere-to-telomere (T2T) genome assemblies illuminate palindromes and multi-copy genes on the Y chromosome</title>
      <link>/event/2024-04-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2024-04-03/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Bio Karol has a Computer Science background but also enjoys the biological aspect of his work. He did his PhD in Oncology analyzing clonal evolution in leukemias. Currently he is focusing on a more standard type of evolution, that of the primate sex chromosomes. He enjoys creating interactive visual representations of his findings. Outside of the lab Karol likes playing music and scuba diving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The DECIPHERD initiative for rare undiagnosed diseases in Chile (and related projects)</title>
      <link>/event/2024-02-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2024-02-14/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Rare diseases affect millions of people worldwide, and most have a genetic etiology. The incorporation of next-generation sequencing into clinical settings, particularly exome and genome sequencing, has resulted in an unprecedented improvement in diagnosis and discovery in the past decade. Nevertheless, these tools are unavailable in many countries, increasing health care gaps between high- and low-and-middle-income countries and prolonging the “diagnostic odyssey” for patients. To advance genomic diagnoses in a setting of limited genomic resources, we developed DECIPHERD, an undiagnosed diseases program in Chile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fourth Annual Retreat of the Center for Medical Genomics (part of the Huck Institutes of the Life Sciences)</title>
      <link>/event/2014-03-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2014-03-25/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Germline Bottleneck, Maternal Age, and Selection Modulate the Transmission Dynamics of Mitochondrial DNA in Human Pedigrees</title>
      <link>/event/2019-10-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2019-10-16/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Resurgence of Reference Quality Genomes using 3rd Generation Sequencing Technologies</title>
      <link>/event/2015-01-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2015-01-06/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The fourth annual retreat for the Center for Medical Genomics</title>
      <link>/event/2013-04-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2013-04-30/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The microRNA landscape of maternal breast milk</title>
      <link>/event/2017-12-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2017-12-06/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The purpose of this workshop is to identify research needs and advance collaborative research efforts on computational and statistical analyses of genomic data.</title>
      <link>/event/2013-10-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2013-10-21/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The rapidly evolving gibbon karyotype as a model to study genome instability</title>
      <link>/event/2016-11-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2016-11-30/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topological and ncRNA influences on inactive X chromosome gene expression</title>
      <link>/event/2014-05-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2014-05-09/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Plasmid Heteroplasmy in Experimental Evolution</title>
      <link>/event/2019-12-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2019-12-04/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcriptome Dysregulation in NonAlcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</title>
      <link>/event/2016-09-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2016-09-28/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering regions of ancestral positive selection with ancient and modern DNA</title>
      <link>/event/2017-03-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2017-03-15/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the role of the X chromosome and genetic variations in human diseases</title>
      <link>/event/2021-11-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2021-11-10/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Ancient DNA to Understand Human Evolution and Adaptation</title>
      <link>/event/2021-02-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2021-02-10/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using high-quality gene annotations on complete primate genomes and human pangenomes to study gene evolution</title>
      <link>/event/2025-01-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2025-01-22/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Vertebrate genomics is heading into an era where the release of hundreds of new reference genomes a year is going to be the norm. If we are to effectively engage with the new biology, we need to be able to annotate genes on these genomes in an accurate and efficient manner. Unfortunately, the current state of gene annotation software requires the use of multiple tools and hours of manual curation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variable expression from the inactive X chromosome: identifying tissue and individual differences and role in traits</title>
      <link>/event/2017-05-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2017-05-17/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Genomics Seminar</title>
      <link>/event/2016-01-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/event/2016-01-27/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>